Karen Ma

karenma.me | karenma333@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/karenma333

SUMMARY

Skills Product Strategy | Requirements Gathering | User Research | Technical Design |

Qualitative Ethnography | User Testing | Web Analytics | User Experience Design

Software | Adobe XD | Figma | Sketch | Google Analytics | Looker

EXPERIENCE

NextCapital — Lead Designer

Previously: Full Stack Product Designer

Sept 2019 - Present Oct 2018 - Sept 2019

Led the product design and development of a new feature to increase the size of existing user base by 68% and increase the new user aggregation rate by 5x

- Define product requirements by conducting user research qualitative and quantitative for problem discovery and user testing using SurveyMonkey, UsabilityHub, in-person moderated user testing/research sessions
- Review and defend designs with key stakeholders using UX artifacts such as use case diagrams, user stories, personas, journey maps, and user research data
- Create specifications of user behavior flows and UI designs with references to internal visual design system for successful handoff to developers
- Measure product success and reviewed product improvement opportunities by designing and tracking web analytics using data analytics software, Looker, and built-in Google Analytics.
- Mentor less experienced designers by reviewing user research plans and UI design compliance to internal design system
- Shape design culture through mentorship, hosting Brown Bags, conducting design critiques, and building out new design processes and guidelines by pioneering the incorporation of user research into existing design process

Design4SD — Research Assistant

Jan 2017 - Jun 2017

I worked in the UCSD Design Lab under Steven Dow and Narges Mayhar working on investigating better ways to encourage and promote participatory design when it comes to civic design challenges. Check out the current status of the project here - https://d4sd.org/.

- Contributed to secondary research by reading existing literature on solutions and their shortcomings
- Conducted interviews with stakeholders in current mobility projects in Downtown San Diego as well as with leaders of civic engagement workshops in San Diego
- Prototyped a civic engagement process design involving mentoring student groups to solve mobility challenges.

EDUCATION

University of California, San Diego BS Cognitive Science (Human Computer Interaction) — 2018 Minor: Computer Science

ACTIVITIES

Industry Advisor - America Needs You

June 2020 - Sept 2020